<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMware on ygerber</title>
    <link>/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMware on ygerber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022-2023, Y.Gerber &amp; Authors</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:13:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSAN Network Considerations</title>
      <link>/post/vmware-vsan-network-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:13:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vmware-vsan-network-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Intro VMware vSAN is a Hyperconverged Infrastructure Solution from VMware. It basically turns your servers direct attached disks into a storage cluster.&#xA;General Requirements 10 GbE network switches are the minimum requirement for all-flash vSAN Clusters 25 GBE network switches are recommended Switches that support higher port speeds are designed with higher Network Processor Unit (NPU) buffers. An NPU shared switch buffer of at least 16 MB is recommended for 10 GbE network connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Monitoring with Grafana</title>
      <link>/post/vsphere-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 20:43:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vsphere-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Intro This blog post describes a solution for monitoring your SDDC Infrastructure with Telegraf, InfluxDB and Grafana. The solution is based on docker and will present graphs and metrics through grafana.&#xA;vSphere Monitoring with TIG (Telegraf, InfluxDB, Grafana) TL;DR: https://github.com/varmox/vsphere-monitoring.git&#xA;Prerequiries RHEL based Linux Docker &amp;amp; Docker Compose (or Podman with Docker Compose. In this tutorial we are using docker &amp;amp; docker compose) installed 3 internal IPs for telegraf, grafana and influxdb containers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quicktip: Tanzu &amp; HA-Proxy</title>
      <link>/post/tanzu-ha-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 20:43:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tanzu-ha-proxy/</guid>
      <description>Quick Tip: vSphere with Tanzu an HA-Proxy This is a short article with tips and tricks I experienced when deploying vSphere with Tanzu and HA-Proxy as a Load Balancer.&#xA;Deploying Ha-Proxy OVA Network&#xA;Alwasys use three NICs when deploying in a production environment. It is very important that these IP addresses do not overlap with the address ranges of your workloads and load balancers, or with the gateway itself.&#xA;At first it can be somewhat confusing what networks are needed and which services will be deployed in each network.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
